# **David Jin**

## Full-stack Software Engineer

#### **Contact**

#### **Address**

Montreal, QC H1Y 3E3, Canada

#### **Email**

davidjin.dev@gmail.com

#### LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com/in/david-jin-3004

## **Skills**

## **Programming Languages**

JavaScript, ECMAScript (ES6), TypeScript, Ruby, GraphQL, C++, HTML, CSS, HTML5, SCSS, Solidity, PHP, Python

#### Libraries & Frameworks

React, Vue.js, Node.js, MobX, WebRTC, Web3.js

Express.js, Angular, Redux, Next.js, Django, Laravel

## **Tools & Platforms**

Git, Gulp, Webpack, Netlify, Heroku, Docker, Firebase, Shopify, Ethereum

## **Education**

## **National University of Singapore**

Bachelor's degree in Computer Science 2008-2012

## Other

#### GitHub

github.com/seniordev-ca

#### Homepage

https://davidjin.netlify.app

## **About Me**

Prolific, full stack web developer with +10 years of experience in frontend and backend development. I always try to implement the very best approaches and paradigms. My main goal is to work with ambitious and agile business owners and entrepreneurs who can visualize and describe their ideas. I am proficient in Django/Laravel and modern JavaScript frameworks like React, Vue.js, and Express.js.

## **Relevant Experience**

## **Full-stack Software Engineer**

Freelancer · May 2021 - Present

- Worked as a part-time technical consultant for a sports betting service and Casino
- Worked on token sales and built the exchange API in Node.js and front-end in React.js and TypeScript
- > Built production-ready POS system from scratch with Laravel and React.js

## **Full-stack Engineer**

Surveying Solutions, Inc. - Apr 2019 - Apr 2021

- Worked with Potree to render point clouds from LiDar
- Designed and developed point clouds managing system with AWS
- Used three.js and ol.js to make a 3D panoramic viewer with a map for point clouds and images
- Built several built-in tools, real-time statistics reporting system

## **Software Consultant**

Vinova · Oct 2017 - Mar 2019

- Worked with a team to create React SPAs with an ASP.NET back-end
- Specialized in building Django applications
- > Supported startup companies to build a web and mobile presence
- Worked on a financial analytic SaaS product built by a React front-end

## **Full-stack Developer**

MXGSoft · Mar 2016 - Jul 2017

- > Built a React front-end from an InVision design
- > Worked on Laravel and Express.js back-end development
- > Integrated various third-party libraries like Twilio and Tokbox
- Followed a strictly defined team code quality guide

## **Software Developer**

MalaySoft · Oct 2013 - Dec 2015

- > Developed a learning management system based on Canvas
- Integrated Stripe and PayPal payments
- > Built RESTful APIs used by iOS/Android apps
- Supported the DevOps team to automate CI/CD processes
- Worked closely with the design team and built an Angular front-end from a Sketch file